pccwsolutions.com 2016-10-24

# PRIVACY POLICY STATEMENT

                                                     PRIVACY POLICY STATEMENT
                           PRIVACY POLICY STATEMENT
       PERSONAL DATA (PRIVACY) ORDINANCE - PRIVACY POLICY STATEMENT
GENERAL
This Privacy Policy Statement provides information on the obligations and policies of PCCW
Limited, its subsidiaries, affiliates, and associated companies (the “Company”, “we”, “us” or
“our”) under the Hong Kong SAR Personal Data (Privacy) Ordinance - Cap.486 (the
“Ordinance”).
This Privacy Policy Statement specifically addresses the Company's obligations in respect of
the data privacy laws of the Hong Kong SAR which is one of the most developed data
protection regimes worldwide. The Company believes the principles embedded in the
Ordinance offer no less protection in personal data privacy than those in other jurisdictions.
As such, the Company undertakes to apply, where practicable, those principles and the
processes set out herein to its operations globally.
Where the Company's operations are subject to privacy legislation other than that of Hong
Kong SAR, then this Privacy Policy Statement shall be applied so far as practicable and
consistent with such local legislation. For further details on the Company's compliance with
the Ordinance and any other privacy legislations, please contact Privacy Compliance Officer at
the address listed below.
Throughout this Privacy Policy Statement, the meaning of the term “personal data” is as
defined in the Ordinance.
COMPANY CORPORATE POLICY
The Company shall fully comply with the obligations and requirements of the Ordinance. The
Company's officers, management, and members of staff shall, at all times, respect the
confidentiality of and endeavour to keep safe any and all personal data collected and/or
stored and/or transmitted and/or used for, or on behalf of, the Company.
The Company shall endeavour to ensure all collection, storage, transmission and other
handling or usage of personal data by the Company shall be done in accordance with the
obligations and requirements of the Ordinance.
Where an individual legitimately requests access to and/or correction of personal data relating
to the individual, held by the Company, then the Company may provide and/or correct that
data in accordance with the time and manner stipulated within the Ordinance.
PUBLIC AVAILABILITY                          October 2015                               Page 1 of 10
Reference: PCO-POL-02                                          Issued by: Privacy Compliance Officer

                                                             PRIVACY POLICY STATEMENT
STATEMENT OF PRACTICES
TYPES OF PERSONAL DATA COLLECTED FROM OR COMPILED FOR CUSTOMERS
For the purpose of carrying on the Company's businesses, including sale, provision, registration and
administration of the Company's telecommunications and related products and services (including
relevant online services and billing service), you as our customer may be requested to provide
personal data such as, but not limited to, the following, without which it may not be possible to
satisfy your request:
       (a) Your name;
       (b) Service installation address, correspondence address, and/or billing address;
       (c) Account details, including account numbers, service numbers, or user accounts;
       (d) Payment details, including credit card and banking information;
       (e) Contact details, including contact name and telephone number or email address; or
       (f) Information for the verification of identity, including identification type and identification
           number.
In some instances, you may also be requested to provide certain data that may be used to further
improve the Company’s products and services and/or better tailor the type of information presented
to you. In most cases, this type of data is optional although, where the requested service is a
personalised service, or provision of a product is dependent on your providing all requested data,
failure to provide the requested data may prevent the Company from providing the service to you.
This type of data may sometimes include, but is not limited to:
       (a) Your age;
       (b) Gender;
       (c) Salary range and employment details;
       (d) Education and Profession;
       (e) Hobbies and leisure activities;
       (f) Other related products and services subscribed to; and
       (g) Family and household demographics.
In support of the telecommunications and other services offered by the Company, information may
be automatically collected relating to those services so the Company may perform accurate
reporting and administration of your accounts such as, but not limited to, call/connection time,
duration, origin, and destination.
The Company's web servers may also collect data relating to your online session, the use of which is
to provide aggregated, anonymous, statistical information so that the Company may better meet the
demands and expectations of visitors to its sites, and take necessary actions in respect of any illegal
or unlawful contents on any website visited through the Company’s web servers. The types of data
may include, but are not limited to:
       (a) The browser type and version;
       (b) Operating system;
       (c) The IP address and/or domain name; and
       (d) URLs.
PUBLIC AVAILABILITY                          October 2015                                   Page 2 of 10
Reference: PCO-POL-02                                              Issued by: Privacy Compliance Officer

                                                          PRIVACY POLICY STATEMENT
Some of the Company's web sites may place a “cookie” on your machine; for example to provide
personalised services and/or maintain your identity across multiple pages within or across one or
more sessions. This information may include, but is not limited to, relevant login and authentication
details as well as information relating to your activities and preferences across the Company’s web
sites.
You can disable cookies on your web browser, however if you do so you may not be able to access
all parts of our web sites.
Occasionally, you may need to provide personal data about other individuals to us (e.g. users whom
you have subscribed for services on their behalf). In that event, for the compliance with the
Ordinance, you are required to have first obtained the authorization of such individuals before using,
disclosing and transferring their personal data, including giving consent on their behalf to our
possible use, disclosure and transfer of their personal data, for the purposes you would want to
achieve from us. If necessary, we may require you to provide us with any supporting document as
may be necessary to prove such authorization. You should also advise them that we can be
contacted for further information (please refer to the section titled “The Company’s Personal Data
(Privacy) Ordinance Contact Details” for our contact details).
Under certain circumstances, telephone calls made to and from the Company’s order and/or service
hotlines and/or inquiry telephone numbers will be recorded for the purposes of quality control,
appraisal, as well as staff management and development. Unless expressly indicated otherwise at
the time of calling, such recordings are NOT personal data of the caller and therefore, in respect of
the caller, are not subject to the various provisions of the Ordinance and the caller has no rights
and/or claims either statutory, contractual or tortious, over or to such data. At all times, care is
taken to protect such recordings from inadvertent and/or unauthorized access.
Any personal data supplied by you will be retained by the Company and will be accessible by our
employees and third parties (as applicable) for the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy Statement
or as otherwise indicated by prior notice to you.
USE OF PERSONAL DATA
Your personal data may be used for:
     verifying your identity;
     processing of your application to subscribe to our services and loyalty programs;
     provision of goods, services and loyalty programs to you;
     administration and management of those goods, services and loyalty programs which you have
      subscribed to, including the renewal of service contracts;
     matching (as defined in the Ordinance) your personal data with other data collected for other
      purposes and from other sources including third parties in relation to the provision of goods,
      services and loyalty programs to you;
     marketing and advertising of any goods, services and/or loyalty programs to you by the
      Company, related companies, agents, contractors and third party suppliers upon your consent
      in accordance with the prevailing requirements in the Ordinance;
PUBLIC AVAILABILITY                         October 2015                                 Page 3 of 10
Reference: PCO-POL-02                                           Issued by: Privacy Compliance Officer

                                                          PRIVACY POLICY STATEMENT
    business planning and improving goods, services and/or loyalty programs for supply to you, by
     the Company, related companies, agents, contractors and third party suppliers, which may be
     performed by various means including without limitation research, analyses and/or surveys;
    processing of any benefits in connection with the supply of goods and services to you;
    analysing, verifying, enforcing contractual rights, and/or checking of your credit, payment
     and/or status in relation to supply of goods and services to you;
    processing of any payment instructions, direct debit facilities and/or credit facilities in relation
     to supply of goods and services to you;
    enabling the daily operation of your account and/or the collection of amounts outstanding in
     your account with the Company including the use of debt collection agents;
    enabling the Company to comply with any obligations to interconnect, with other industry
     practices, or with obligations to third parties or government agencies in relation to the supply
     of goods and services to you;
    maintaining and developing our business systems and infrastructure, including testing and
     upgrading of these systems;
    keeping you informed about goods and services supplied to you and other goods and services
     made available by the Company;
    prevention, detection or investigation of crime;
    disclosure as permitted or required by law; and/or
    any other purposes as may be agreed to between you and the Company, including the
     purposes set out in any application or terms and conditions for the supply of specific goods and
     services.
ACCURACY OF PERSONAL DATA
Where possible, the Company will validate data provided using generally accepted practices and
guidelines. This includes the use of check sum verification on some numeric fields such as account
numbers or credit card numbers. In some instances, the data provided will be validated against pre-
existing data held by the Company. In some cases, as per the requirements of the Ordinance, the
Company is required to see original documentation before the personal data may be used, such as
with Personal Identifiers and/or proof of address. For the purpose of ensuring accuracy or
authenticity of the identity document supplied to us, we expect customer to produce customer’s
identity document in person for checking at a time convenient to customer. Customer may call our
Customer Service Hotline for the necessary arrangement.
The Company fully complies with the “Rights of Access and Correction” obligations of the Ordinance.
Please refer to the section titled “Access and Correction of Personal Data” below for details on how
you can obtain and correct any personal data relating to you that the Company may hold.
Please note that the accuracy of such personal data we collect, use and disclose depends to a large
extent on the information you provide. You have a right to request correction of your personal data
and we recommend that you:
PUBLIC AVAILABILITY                         October 2015                                Page 4 of 10
Reference: PCO-POL-02                                          Issued by: Privacy Compliance Officer

                                                          PRIVACY POLICY STATEMENT
    let us know if there are any errors in your personal data; and
    keep us up-to-date with changes to your personal data such as your name or address.
RETENTION OF PERSONAL DATA
The Company will destroy any personal data it may hold in accordance with its internal policy.
Generally speaking, the Company’s policies cover the following principles:
       (a)   personal data will only be retained for as long as is necessary to fulfil the original or
             directly related purposes for which it was collected, unless the personal data is also
             retained to satisfy any applicable statutory or contractual obligations; and
       (b)   personal data are purged from the Company's electronic, manual, and other filing
             systems in accordance with specific schedules based on the above criteria and the
             Company's internal procedures.
DISCLOSURE OF PERSONAL DATA
All personal data held by the Company will be kept confidential but the Company may, where such
disclosure is necessary to satisfy the purpose, or a directly related purpose, for which the data was
collected provide such information to the following parties:
       (a)   any subsidiaries, holding companies, associated companies, or affiliates of, or
             companies controlled by, or under common control with the Company;
       (b)   any person or company who is acting for or on behalf of the Company, or jointly with
             the Company, in respect of the purpose or a directly related purpose for which the data
             was provided;
       (c)   any other person or company who is under a duty of confidentiality to the Company and
             has undertaken to keep such information confidential, provided such person or company
             has a legitimate right to such information;
       (d)   the Company’s dealers, agents, contractors, suppliers and other telecommunication,
             information service providers and content providers; its professional advisers, including
             its accountants, auditors and lawyers;
       (e)   government and regulatory authorities and law enforcement agencies and other
             organisations, as required or authorised by law;
       (f)   any financial institutions, charge or credit card issuing companies, credit providers,
             credit information or reference bureaux, or collection agencies, security agencies,
             necessary to establish and support the payment of any services being requested;
       (g)   your authorized representatives or your legal advisers when requested by you to do so;
       (h)   telecommunications network operators;
       (i)   banks, hotels, insurance companies, billing agents and various business partners for
             reward redemption purposes and benefits as applicable to members of our loyalty
             programs, including without limitation for purposes of registering members for loyalty
             program related events;
       (j)   organisations who manage our business and corporate strategies (and for such
             purposes), including those involved in a transfer/sale of all or part of our assets or
             business (including accounts and trade receivables) and those involved in managing our
             corporate risk and funding functions (e.g. securitisation); and
PUBLIC AVAILABILITY                         October 2015                                 Page 5 of 10
Reference: PCO-POL-02                                           Issued by: Privacy Compliance Officer

                                                          PRIVACY POLICY STATEMENT
       (k)   any proposed or actual participant, assignee or transferee of all or any part of the
             Company's operation or business.
Personal data may also be disclosed to any person or persons pursuant to any statutory or
contractual obligations or as required by court of law, provided such person or persons are able to
prove the required right/authority to access such information. In addition, personal data may be
disclosed under any of the circumstances described in Part VIII of the Ordinance in which the
concerned personal data are exempt from the provisions of Data Protection Principle 3 of the
Ordinance.
TRANSFER OF PERSONAL DATA OUTSIDE HONG KONG
At times it may be necessary and/or prudent for the Company to transfer certain personal data to
places outside the Hong Kong SAR in order to carry out the purposes, or directly related purposes,
for which the personal data were collected. Where such a transfer is performed, it will be done in
compliance with the prevailing requirements of the Ordinance.
SECURITY OF PERSONAL DATA
Physical records containing personal data are securely stored in locked areas and/or containers
when not in use.
Computer data are stored on computer systems and storage media to which access is strictly
controlled and/or are located within restricted areas.
Access to records and data without appropriate management authorization are strictly prohibited.
Authorizations are granted only on a “need to know” basis that is commensurate with an individual's
Company responsibilities and their training.
Where the Company holds, uses and/or transmits the Customers’ personal data it will be adequately
protected from accidental and/or unauthorized disclosure, change and/or destruction.
You should be aware that no system is impenetrable and no information provided over the Internet
can be guaranteed to be completely secure. Accordingly, we cannot guarantee the security of any
information that you transmit to us or receive from us over the Internet.
LINKS TO THIRD PARTY WEBSITES
Our websites (including www.pccw.com, www.hkt.com and www.hkcsl.com) may contain links to
other sites and pages which are operated by third parties. We have no control over the content of
the linked websites or the way in which the operators of those websites deal with your personal data.
You should review the privacy policy for those third party websites to understand the ways in which
your personal data may be used by those third parties.
ACCESS AND CORRECTION OF PERSONAL DATA
Under the Ordinance, individuals have the right to:
       (a)   ascertain whether the Company holds any personal data relating to them and, if so,
             obtain copies of such data (“right of access”);
       (b)   require the Company to correct personal data in its possession which is inaccurate for
             the purpose for which it is being used by means of a data access request (right of
             correction); and
PUBLIC AVAILABILITY                         October 2015                               Page 6 of 10
Reference: PCO-POL-02                                         Issued by: Privacy Compliance Officer

                                                             PRIVACY POLICY STATEMENT
       (c)    ascertain the Company's policies and practices in relation to personal data, which are
              those policies and practices set out in their entirety herein.
An individual may exercise his or her right of access by:
       (a)    completing the “Data Access Request Form” as prescribed by the Privacy Commissioner
              for Personal Data or the “Personal Data (Privacy) Ordinance - Data Access Request
              Form” - see “Note 1” below;
       (b)    sending the completed form, along with appropriate proof of identity (a copy of the
              applicant's Hong Kong Identity Card or Passport) and the prescribed fee to the
              Company's Privacy Compliance Officer at the address listed below;
       (c)    alternatively, if you do not wish to provide a copy of your proof of identity, you may
              present the completed form - see “Note 1” below - in person, along with appropriate
              identification, at any of the conveniently located “Customer Service Centers” listed
              below. There, staff will verify your identity and stamp the completed form appropriately.
              Please send the stamped form and processing fee to Privacy Compliance Officer (Group
              Legal Office) at the address listed below for processing.
The Company will, upon satisfying itself of the authenticity and validity of the access request, make
every endeavour to comply with and respond to the request within the period set by the Ordinance
(i. e. within 40 days after receiving the request).
An individual may exercise their right of correction by writing to the Company's Privacy Compliance
Officer at the address listed below, specifying the data obtained through the Data Access Request
mentioned above which needs to be corrected.
Satisfactory proof and/or explanation of the inaccuracy is essential before the Company would
consider correcting the specified data.
Upon satisfying itself of the authenticity and validity of the correction request, the Company will
comply with and respond to the request as required by the Ordinance.
DIRECT MARKETING
In accordance with the requirements of the Ordinance, the Company will honour a customer's
request not to use his or her personal data for the purposes of direct marketing.
Upon customer’s consent, the Company may use his or her personal data (including name, contact
information, and information about the products, services, or loyalty programs that he or she has
purchased or subscribed to) to deliver to customer, through various communication channels by
using email address, correspondence address, mobile phone number, telephone number, service
number and service account number, etc., various promotion materials including the Company’s
latest offers, gifts, discounts, benefits, information relating to telecommunications network services
(all services or products operating or can be operated on HKT’s telecommunications network such as
TV, mobile voice, SMS and data communications, IDD/roaming, Internet connectivity, cloud services,
entertainment and data communications on Internet), computer peripheral, accessories and
software (including notebooks, handsets, mobile devices and accessories, keyboards, security
installations and mobile applications), secretarial services, personal assistance services and
information services. Customer may also be provided with the latest offers on various kinds of
products or services including gaming, sports, music, beauty products, electronics, technology, e-
commerce, cloud services, mobile payment, travelling, banking, investment, entertainment,
transportation, household, fashion, food and beverages, alcohol and tobacco, insurance, education,
health and wellness, social networking, media and high-end consumer products and services. For the
PUBLIC AVAILABILITY                           October 2015                                 Page 7 of 10
Reference: PCO-POL-02                                             Issued by: Privacy Compliance Officer

                                                             PRIVACY POLICY STATEMENT
avoidance of doubt, this consent is separate from and independent of customer’s services registered
with the PCCW Group or the HKT Group. Accordingly, it can be withdrawn at any time as per this
Privacy Policy without reference to the duration of the services, and will survive the termination or
expiration of customer’s service contracts.
Customer can at any time send request to our Privacy Compliance Officer together with registered
name and service account number, registered service number or login name, to stop receiving the
promotion materials aforesaid or to start receiving the same (if customers have unsubscribed from
receiving such materials before).
Any such request should clearly state the details of the personal data in respect of which the request
is being made. Specifically, it is requested that you include the corresponding Company assigned
account numbers which are printed on the Company's statements/invoices.
HANDLING OF PERSONAL DATA IN RECRUITMENT AND EMPLOYMENT
RECRUITMENT
During the recruitment process, job applicants may be required to provide sufficient personal data
so that the Company may, as appropriate and/or applicable:
       (a) assess the applicant's suitability for the position being applied for;
       (b) assess the applicant's suitability for other positions the Company may have available;
       (c) determine preliminary remuneration and benefit packages;
       (d) verification of credentials and/or experience; and
       (e) perform security vetting and/or integrity checking.
At a minimum, such personal data will include:
       (a) the applicant's name and contact details, including address and telephone number(s);
       (b) previous employment and relevant experience; and
       (c) education and relevant training.
Additional information may also be required dependent on the nature of the position being applied
for.
The applicant is responsible for ensuring all personal data they provide is accurate and complete.
The provision of inaccurate information or the withholding of requested information may:
       (a)    prevent the Company from making an offer of employment;
       (b)    invalidate such offer if the inaccuracy or omission is discovered after an offer has been
              made; or
       (c)    lead to termination of employment if the inaccuracy or omission is discovered after
              employment has commenced.
The personal data so provided may be transferred to persons within the Company, its associated
companies, and its clients in client projects; who are involved in the assessment of the applicant's
suitability for the position applied for and/or other positions, which may be, or may become,
PUBLIC AVAILABILITY                           October 2015                                 Page 8 of 10
Reference: PCO-POL-02                                             Issued by: Privacy Compliance Officer

                                                          PRIVACY POLICY STATEMENT
available within the Company. The data may also be transferred to third parties, such as
investigation agencies or previous employer, as are necessary to satisfy the purposes set out above.
The Company shall retain the personal data of unsuccessful applicants for future recruitment
purposes for a period of not exceeding two years from the day on which the recruitment period ends.
The personal data of successful applicants shall be retained for the duration of their employment by
the Company and as described below under the heading of “Employment, Including Post
Employment”.
In respect of the Company's practices regarding matters not directly addressed in this section
“Recruitment”, the practices, and procedures set out in the preceding sections of this Privacy Policy
Statement shall apply.
EMPLOYMENT, INCLUDING POST EMPLOYMENT
In the course of employment by the Company, personal data of employees and their families, as
appropriate, will be collected and used on an ongoing basis for various Human Resource purposes
including but not limited to; administering staffing, performance management, training, career
development, salary and benefits administration, communication (e.g. Company news, staff benefit
offerings and promotions), medical benefits, provident fund administration, insurance, taxation,
welfare and providing information in compliance with legal requirements. It will be transferred to
those internal departments, intra-company, and/or to other third parties as is necessary for the
purposes.
The Company retains certain personal data of employees when they cease to be employed by the
Company (and such data will be retained for no longer than seven years after their cessation of
employment). Such data are required for any residual employment-related activities of the former
employee including, but not limited to:
       (a) The provision of job references;
       (b) Processing applications for re-employment;
       (c) Matters relating to retirement benefits; and
       (d) Allowing the Company to fulfil contractual or statutory obligations.
Further details regarding the Company's policies and practices in respect of its handling of personal
data relating to its employees, including post employment, are included in the Company's Human
Resources Policies and Staff Handbooks. They are also available to the Company's employees from
either the Company's Privacy Compliance Officer or directly from their respective Human Resources
representative.
THE COMPANY'S PERSONAL DATA (PRIVACY) ORDINANCE CONTACT DETAILS
All enquiries regarding the Company's compliance with its obligations under the Ordinance should be
in writing to:
(i)    For mobile services –
       CSL Mobile Limited (香港移動通訊有限公司)（“CSL”）
       Privacy Compliance Officer
       PO Box 9872, GPO, Hong Kong
       Or email to: privacy@hkcsl.com
PUBLIC AVAILABILITY                         October 2015                                 Page 9 of 10
Reference: PCO-POL-02                                           Issued by: Privacy Compliance Officer

                                                         PRIVACY POLICY STATEMENT
      If you wish to stop receiving direct marketing materials from CSL, please write to the address
      above or email to dmprivacy@hkcsl.com along with your registered name and service account
      number or registered service number and specify the direct marketing communication channel
      that you would want to reject.
(ii)  For services other than mobile services –
      PCCW Limited
      Privacy Compliance Officer
      PO Box 9896, GPO, Hong Kong
      Or email to: privacy@pccw.com
      If you wish to stop receiving direct marketing materials from PCCW Limited or subsidiaries of
      PCCW Limited (other than CSL ), please write to the address above or email to
      opt-out@pccw.com along with your registered name and service account number, registered
      service number or login name, and specify the direct marketing communication channel that
      you would want to reject.
Customer Service Centers:
      Area              Address
      Wan Chai          Basement, Lockhart Exchange, 3 Hennessy Road, Wan Chai, Hong Kong
                        (MTR Wan Chai exit B1, next to Asian House)
      Tsim Sha Tsui     3/F Hermes House, 10 Middle Road, Tsimshatsui, Kowloon, Hong Kong
                        (MTR Tsim Sha Tsui exit L1, entrance nearby Minden Row, between TST
                        Post Office and Mariners' Club)
      Tsuen Wan         G/F, Tsuen Wan Exchange, 303 Castle Peak Road, Tsuen Wan, New
                        Territories
                        (MTR Tsuen Wan Station Exit A, opposite to Tsuen Kam Center)
Note 1:
The Company will handle requests made either on its own form, “Personal Data (Privacy) Ordinance
- Data Access Request Form” (PCCW/PCO-TEM-01), or on that prescribed by the Hong Kong SAR
Privacy Commissioner for Personal Data (Form OPS003 [revised 09/2012]), provided all mandatory
data as specified in the relevant form has been supplied.
(This Privacy Policy Statement may be amended from time to time and all handling of personal data
will be governed by the most recent version of this Privacy Policy Statement, available on our
website at www.pccw.com. If there is any inconsistency or conflict between the English and Chinese
versions, the English version shall prevail.)
PUBLIC AVAILABILITY                         October 2015                             Page 10 of 10
Reference: PCO-POL-02                                         Issued by: Privacy Compliance Officer
